Brave Exkaiser
勇 者 エクスカイザ- 용자 엑스카이저
Over a million of them shine with a blue light
靑く輝く 幾千万の 푸르게 빛나는 몇천만개의
The shards of love have scattered
愛のかけらが ちりばめられた 사랑의 조각들이 흩어져 있어
It's brewing in this world
この 地球(ほし)の中 蠢く 이 지구 안에 휘몰아치는
A storm that you'll confront
嵐に向かう 폭풍우로 달려가는
And because I believe in you
君を信じたから 너를 믿으니까
I'm not afraid of anything
何も恐れないさ 아무것도 두렵지 않아
GO WITH ME Exkaiser
GO WITH ME エクスカイザ-！ GO WITH ME 엑스카이저!
Courage and friendship
勇氣と友情！ 용기와 우정!
That moment when we join our strength GATHER WAY
力 あわせた その 時 GATHER AWAY 힘을 합치는 그순간 GATHER AWAY
GO WITH ME Exkaiser
GO WITH ME エクスカイザ-！ GO WITH ME 엑스카이저!
I'd almost forgotten it
忘れかけていた！ 잊고 있었던
The fiery burning and important PASSIONATE feeling in my heart
熱く 燃える 大切な PASSIONATE この 胸に 뜨겁게 불타는 소중한 PASSIONATE내 가슴에!
This mysterious and boundless Universe...
신비하고 광대한 우주 성우:山寺宏一야마데라 코이치
It was here that the evil energy life forms, the space pirate Geisters,
이 우주에 깃든 악의 에너지 생명체 우주 해적 가이스터가
set their sights on the treasures of humans and snuck onto Earth.
인류의 보물을 노리고 지구로 잠입했다
However, thwarting their lust for devastation, the perfect hero stands in their way.
하지만 파괴와 약탈을 일삼으며 싸우는 가이스터 앞에
He is Exkaiser of the cosmic police.
우주 경찰 엑스카이저다
This is the story of the battle between good and evil that has spanned across the universe,
이것은 우주에 퍼지고 있는 악과 싸우는
and of brave Exkaiser and his comrades.
용자 엑스카이저와 그 동료들의 이야기이다
Mars Orbital Rocket, Launch!
第４話　火星行きロケットしゅっぱ-つ！ 第４話　화성으로 가는 로켓 출발! 1990/2/24
Alright! All set!
됐다, 준비 완료!
I'm done as well.
나도 다 됐어
Okay, I'll be the one to count down!
알았지? 내가 다 세면 발사하는 거다
It's perfectly clear who's going to come out on top.
내가 이기는 건 뻔할 뻔자지만!
My rocket is awesome, you'll see.
내 로봇이 더 높이 날아갈거야! 잘 보라구!
Okay, I'll count from five.
그럼 이제 카운트다운 한다!
Launch!
발사!
Go!
출발!
Hmph! Well, what did you expect?
흥, 뭐 그게 그렇지 뭐!
This clearly shows that I won.
이걸로 내가 이겼군
Well? It flew this high with its size!
어때? 이정도의 크기지만 엄청 잘 날지?
Seems this one is a draw...
이번 승부는 무승부다
Don't you think regular toy rockets are boring, Kotomi-chan?
장난감 로켓은 좀 시시하지 않아? 그렇지, 코토미?
How about we go see the real thing?
진짜 로켓 보러 안갈래?
The Mars Orbital rocket is going to launch in two days. Papa managed to get wonderful seats.
모레 화성행 발사가 있거든 아빠가 돈으로 좋은 좌석을 잡았거든
Really? That's great!
정말? 굉장하다~
You know it!
그렇지?
Kouta-kun, you'll come too, right?
코우타도 가는 거지?
Eh? Can I?
에? 가도 되는 거야?
Right? Is it alright for Kouta-kunn to come along?
괜찮지? 코우타도 가도 되는 거지?
I guess...
좋을대로...
This should be the place.
여기야, 여기
Where's the rocket?
어느 게 로켓이야?
I got it!
여깄다!
This must be it!
이거다!
Alright, swipe it!
좋아, 가져가자!
Got it...
굉장하군
What's that?
뭐지?
Maybe we'll mess things up a bit...
약간 난리법석 좀 떨어주고 가자구!
This should be enough. Let's go.
이 정도면 됐다, 가자!
We'll walk away like nothing happened..
어, 가자..
This is terrible...
이것참 말이 아니군
Oh, chief!
아! 편집장님! 성우:山寺宏一야마데라 코이치
What in the world happened?
도대체 무슨 일이 일어난 건가?
As you can see, the rocket hangar was destroyed.
보시는 대로입니다 성우:山寺宏一야마데라 코이치
I see that! I'm asking who would do such a thing for what reason!
그건 알고 있어! 누가 뭣때문에 이런 짓을 했는지 묻는 거잖아!
Please, don't fret.
다그치지 마세요
The police have only just begun their investigation. They don't know anything yet..
경찰조사도 이제 막 시작 되서 알려진 사실이 아무 것도 없거든요
Except...
그런데..
Except what?
그런데 뭔가?
They know for sure that the culprit stole the model rocket on display.
범인이 전시용의 모형 로켓을 훔쳐갔다는 것만은 확실합니다
The model rocket?
전시용 로켓을?
Yeah, and this is my conclusion!
네, 이건 제 소견입니다만..
The culprit is nothing more than a rocket fan!
결국 로켓메니아가 아닐까요?
A rocket fan?
로켓메니아?
Yup!
네!
And why would a rocket fan destroy the hangar?
로켓메니아가 어째서 공장까지 파괴했다고 생각하나?
Oh, I do wonder...
아~ 왜 그랬을까요?
Idiot!
이 못난 사람아!
Finding that out is your job!
그걸 취재하는 게 자네 일이잖아!
Stop standing around and go do the job!
멍하게 있지 말고 일하러나 가!
Yes! Understood!
네, 알겠습니다!
Why could havve done such a thing...
대체 누가 이런 짓을 한거지?
This is a fake.
이건 가짜다!
Nothing more than a trinket!
그저 쓰레기일 뿐이야!
I ordered to deliver the real rocket to here...
나는 진짜 로켓을 가져오라고 한거다
If you understood, then get lost!
알아들었으면 어서 가라!
Dino Geist-sama is angry!
다이노 가이스터님이 노하셨다!
Who's responsible for stealing that fake!?
저런 가짜를 훔쳐오다니 누가 책임질거냐?
It was you!
니가 책임져!
I only said that might be it.
난 이게 아닐까 한마디 한 것밖에 없어
Horn Geist told us to take it.
혼가이스터가 가져가자고 그랬어
What!? You want a fight?
뭐여? 니 말 듣고 가져가자고 한 거지!
That's not what I meant--
야, 난 그런 뜻으로 한 얘기가...
Shut up!
시끄러~~~~!!
The Mars rocket is going to launch in the morning.
내일 아침 화성행 로켓을 발사한다
Steal it before it takes off!
그 전에 무슨 수를 써서든 로켓을 뺏어와!
Leave it to me.
내가 하도록 하지
Those guys are uselesss.
그 녀석들은 틀렸어
I'm the one with the brains.
빈틈없이 내가 해결하지
Exkaiser, are you awake?
엑스카이저, 자?
I'm awake, Kouta.
깨어 있다, 코우타
I heard that the rocket hangar was attacked.
로켓 공장이 습격당했다며?
Yes..
그래
Who could hae done that?
누가 그런 짓을 한거야?
We still don't know yet.
아직 알아내지 못했다
But didn't they leave everything behind?
하지만 아무 것도 잃어버린 건 없었던 거지?
A model rocket for display was stolen but nothing of any value was taken.
전시용 로켓 한 대가 사라지긴 했다는데 도움이 될 만한 자료는 그것뿐인 듯 하다
That's weird.
이상하네...
But I'm glad the Mars rocket wasn't destroyed.
하지만 화성행 로켓이 파괴된 게 아니라 다행이야
It took me 3 hours to fix this thing!
이렇게 작은 것도 고치는데 3시간이나 걸렸거든
You sure like rockets, Kouta.
코우타는 로켓을 좋아하는구나
Yup. I know that you came from space, so you must know that all those stars inn the sky are suns, right?
음..엑스카이저는 우주에서 왔으니까 아는 사실이겠지만
That's right. The galaxy that you live in has over 2 billion stars.
그래, 코우타가 있는 이 은하계는 약 2천억개의 별로 만들어져 있다 地球は數千億個からの銀河系からなり
And this galaxy is but one of many galaxies in the entire universe.
그리고 전 우주에는 그런 은하계가 수천억개가 있지 宇宙にはその銀河系が數千億個ある
That's awesome!
굉장하다~
When I grow up, I want to journey through the universe!
난 크면 이 넓은 우주를 모험하고 싶어
My dream is to become the pilot of a rocket and travel into space!
언젠가 우주로켓의 파일럿이 되서 우주를 날아서 돌아다니는 게 내 꿈이야
That's a good dream.
좋은 꿈이다
Tomorrow's rocket will head to Mars to set up a Mars base...
내일 발사될 화성행의 로켓은 화성에 우주기지를 설치를 위해 반드시 필요한 로켓이야
So it's something that's needed to make further advances in space travel, right?
우주로 나가기 위한 전선기지라는 거지?
Yup! that's why that rocket has to make it to Mars or it'll be a huge roadblock to us.
음, 그러니까 그 로켓은 반드시 화성에 가지 않으면 안되는 거야
Someday, we have to board on rockets and explore space in someday.
우리들도 언젠가는 그 로켓을 타고 우주 탐험을 해야 하거든
Kouta, you will definitely make it.
코우타, 반드시 가게 될거다
Right.
음!
-Woah! It's huge! -It's incredible!
와~~ 엄청 크다~ /굉장해~
When I grow up, I'm going to be a rocket pilot!
나 어른이 되면 로켓 파일럿이 될거야
That's great! When that happens, you better be sure to give me a ride!
멋지다~ 그때 나도 꼭 타워줘~
You think too small.
하찮구만 하찮아!
One day, I will buy a rocket like that and give it to you as a present, Kotomi-chan.
코토미, 난 언제가 저 것보다 더 큰 로켓을 사서 너한테 선물로 줄께
Kotomi-chan?
코토미?
Hey! Don't to off without me!
야! 네들 멋대로 가면 안돼!
Wait for me!
기다려 달란 말야~
Hey! Don't push!
이봐! 밀지마!
Out of the way!
비켜요 비켜!
Everyone, take a look at this historical moment!
여러분, 이 역사적인 광경을 보십시요!
Soon, this Mars rocket will head off and build humanity a Mars base.
곧 인류 최초의 화성 기지를 만들 로켓이 발사되려는 순간입니다
With this rocket's success, it'll instantly build a clear path to outer space for humans.
이 로켓 발사가 성공한다면
There's still 30 minutes and 12 seconds until launch.
발사는 앞으로 30분 후인 12시 정각으로 되어 있습니다
With all humans' dreams aboard, it will depart to Mars!
인류의 꿈을 싣고 화성으로 날아가는 것입니다
Ah, uh... you're hurting me...
아...잠깐...저어..아파라...
The rocket will be entering takeoff preparations shortly.
곧 로켓이 발사대로 들어갈 것입니다
The countdown is important for the launch.
이 발사 타이밍이 중요한 거거든
Why?
왜?
Well, because it's obvious that it'll take off at 12 o'clock...
아니..그러니까 12시에 발사하는 게 당연하니까...
Why is it 12 o'clock?
왜 12시인데?
Because... uh...
그러니까..그건...
If they don't get the launch time and angle exactly right,
로켓의 발사 시간과 발사 각도가 제대로 맞지 않으면
the rocket wouldn't be able to make it to the orbital path that leads to Mars.
로켓은 제대로 화성에 도착할 수 있는 궤도에 오를 수 없기 때문이야
It's all administrated from the control center over there.
그걸 제어하고 있는 게 저쪽 저기 관제센터야
Oh, I see... You sure know a lot, Kouta-kun!
아~ 그렇구나 잘 알고 있었구나, 코우타는!
Nah, I don't know everything!
아니, 별 것도 아니야
Tch!
치~
We'll be starting the countdown shortly.
이어서 카운트 다운에 들어가겠습니다
Take off in 5 minutes.
로켓 발사 5분 전
Ah! That's--!
아! 위험해!
Something's flying!
뭔가 날아 왔어
-What's that? -What's going on?
뭐야, 저건? /무슨 일이 벌어지는 거지?
So, this is the rocket that the boss wants...
이게 보스가 말한 로켓 머신이군
With this on it, the rocket is ours.
이 걸 붙여놓으면 로켓은 우리 거란 말씀!
The Geisters!
가이스터야!
Energy Box, start up!
에너지 박스 작동! エネルギ-ボックス Energy box
A scoop!
특종이다!
Unbelievable!
믿을 수가 없군요
How could such a thing happen?
이런 일이 진짜로 벌어질 수 있는 걸까요
The Mars rocket launching pad has transformed into a monster!
화성행 로켓발사대가 괴물로 변해버렸습니다!
Kotomi-chan, hurry!
코토미, 서둘러 어서!
Hey! Don't leave me behind!
야, 나만 두고 가면 어떡해!
That was too easy. Shake this apart apart!
너무 쉽구만 한 번 더 뒤집어 버려!
I have to call Exkaiser!
엑스카이저를 불러야 해!
Exkaiser! The rocket is under attack!
엑스카이저 로켓이 공격당했어
What!?
뭐라고?
Come quickly!
빨리 와줘!
Right!
알았다!
Oh? Was that our car?
어머머, 지금 나간 차 우리차 아니었나?
I guess that's impossible.
그럴 리 없을거야
Blue Raker, Green Raker, the launch pad is under attack!
블루 레이커, 그린 레이커 발사대가 공격당했다
Got it!
알았다!
We're on our way!
바로 가겠다!
Please, hurry!
부탁해 빨리 와줘!
Nii-san, over there!
형님 저깁니다!
Let's go, little brother!
가자, 아우야!
Right!
음!
Change, Blue Raker!
Change! Blue Raker!
Change, Green Raker!
Change! Green Raker!
Raker Brothers!
Raker Brothers! レイカ-ブラザ-ズ 레이커 브라더스!
More robots have appeared!
또 새로운 로봇이 나타났습니다
We've been waiting for you!
기다리고 있었어요!
Seems like they're allies of justice!
다행히도 정의의 우리편인 듯합니다
Geister, you scoundrel!
가이스터 악당놈들!
Return the rocket that carries the hopes of the people!
인류의 꿈을 실은 로켓을! 人人の夢を乘せたロケットを
What the hell!? I won't let you interfere!
무슨 말을 지껄이는 거냐! 방해한다면 봐주지 않겠다!
Go!
가라!
Take this!
받아라!
We won't let you go!
도망가게 놔두지 않아!
Damn you!
이 놈!
Nii-san!
형님!
Oh my lord!
큰 일났습니다
The launch pad is moving on its own!
로켓 발사대가 스스로 움직이고 있습니다
Just what in the world is happening!?
도대체 이건 어떻게 되어가는 걸까요?
At this rate, the rocket won't be able to launch!
이대로는 로켓발사는 어림없어
Exkaiser! Please hurry!
엑스카이저! 어서 빨리 와줘!
If it doesn't launch exactly at noon, it won't make it to the orbital path to Mars!
12시 정각에 발사하지 않으면 로켓은 화성으로 가는 궤도에 오를 수 없게 돼!
Please stop the Geisters!
가이스터를 빨리 처리해줘!
Leave it to me, Kouta!
오래 기다렸다, 코우타!
I'll take care of the rocket!
로켓은 내게 맡겨라!
Change, Exkaiser!
Change! Exkaiser ! チェ-ンジ!  エクスカイザ ! 체인지! 엑스카이저 !
Exkaiser!
엑스카이저!
You--!
네 녀석!
Spike Cutter!
Spike cutter! スパイクカッタ-! 스파이크 커터!
Here comes some more!
Kaiser shot ! カイザ-ショット! 카이저 샷 !
Now!
됐다!
Form Up!
Form Up! フォ-ムオブ! 폼 업!
Left Right Fusion, Ultra Raker!
좌우합체 울트라 레이커! 左右合體ウルトラレイカ-
Damn them... Destroy them!
이 놈들! 해치워버려!
Ultra Kick!
Ultra Kick! ウルトラキック 울트라 킥
Shit...!
빌어먹을!
King Loader!
King Loader キング-ロ-ダ- 킹 로더!
Form Up!
Form Up! フォ-ムオブ! 폼 업!
Giant Fusion, King Exkaiser!
Huge union King Exkaiser 巨大合體 キングエクスカイザ 거대합체 킹엑스카이저!
The robot of justice got bigger!
정의의 로봇이 거대하게 변했습니다
Shit! You became big again!
젠장! 또 커져버렸구만
Go! Destroy them!
공격해! 해치워 버려!
Kaiser Sword!
Kaiser Sword カイザ-ソド 카이저 소드!
That's why the rocket has to
그 로켓은 반드시 화성에 가야해
Yup! that's why that rocket has to make it to Mars or it'll be a huge roadblock to us.
우리들도 언젠가는 그 로켓을 타고 우주 탐험을 해야 하거든
That rocket carries Kouta's dreams... I cannot destroy it.
저 로켓은 코우다와 모두의 꿈이다 파괴해서는 안된다
What should I do!?
어떻게 해야 하지?
Exkaiser! There isn't more time!
엑스카이저 시간이 없어!
There has to be a way to keep the rocket unscathed.
로켓을 손상시키지 않을 방법이 있을거다
There!
저기다!
Getting the angle right will do it!
발사 각도를 맞추면 된다!
That should do it!
이제 됐다!
It launched!
날았다!
Exkaiser...
엑스카이저!
Thunder Flash!
Thunder Flash! サンダ-フラッシュ! 썬더 플래쉬!
They did it! They made it!
해치웠다! 해치웠어!
Shit... I won't forget this!
젠장! 다음에 보자구!
They made it, Kouta-kun!
해냈어, 코우타!
Alright! The rocket's up in the sky!
역시 해냈어! 로켓이 날고 있어!
This time it'll work.
이번에는 분명히 해낼거야
Here we go, Kotomi-chan!
시작한다! 코토미!
Right.
응!
Launch!
발사!
Oh! It's falling!
아! 떨어지고 있어!
Yay!
해냈다!
Faraway wind carries your dream
遙かな 風が 夢を 運んで 아득한 바람이 꿈을 가져와
What could you discover from this excited feeling
ときめく 事に 何を 見つけるの 설레이는 일에서 무엇을 찾아낼까
Dreams get bigger strongly and fast
强く 早く ふくらむ 夢に 강하고 빠르게 부풀어 오르는 꿈에
Don't forget to be who you are
自分らしさ 忘れずに 자신다운 모습을 잊지 말고
Embrace your enthusiastic heart
夢中に なれる 心 抱きしめ 정열적인 마음 꼭 껴안고
And try walking that path
その 道を 步いてみてね 그 길을 걸어가 보는거야
Uwah! It's empty!
わっ! カラッポだ!
All the pharmacies in the city are full of holes!
町中の藥屋さんが穴ぼこだけになっちゃった!
Even hospitals are lacking on medicines, and no one can be cured at this rate!
病院にも藥がないし
Exkaiser!
エクスカイザ-!
Take me to the pharmaceutical factory!
製藥工場へ連れて行って!
You have to get medicine to save Kotomi-chan and everyone!
藥をもらって,コトミちゃんたちを助けなきゃ!
Next on Brave Exkaiser,
次回,勇者エクスカイザ- 『藥屋さんがカラッポ!?』
Is there an alien in your home, too?
君んちにも宇宙人,いる?